building.co.uk 2018-07-24

# Privacy and Cookie Policy | Information - Building | Building

Assemble Media Group is an independent UK based media and events business with offices in central London and Chester. 

This privacy policy governs the collection and use of personal information by Assemble Media Group. 

We are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy. This privacy policy explains the types of personal information we collect, how we use that information, who we share it with, how we protect that information, and your legal rights in relation to your information. We are committed to abiding by this privacy policy, as well as the requirements of applicable laws, in the operation of our business. Please read this policy carefully as it explains our views and practices regarding your personal information and how it is handled. By accessing or browsing our websites, you confirm that you have read, understood and agree to this privacy policy in its entirety. If you do not agree with the practices described in this policy, you should not use this website.

**Who we are**

For the purpose of applicable data protection laws, the data controller is Assemble Media Group 81 Rivington Street, London, EC2A 3AY. Our Data Protection Officer is Tom Broughton.

**Information covered by this policy**

When you access and browse our websites (including when you register for an event or fill in forms on our websites) and when you correspond with us by phone or email or other electronic means, you may give us information about yourself. The information you give us may include your name, payment processing information, postal address, email address, landline and/or mobile telephone number, delivery details, payment processing information, dietary and access requirements and information about your employment (including your job title, responsibilities and employer’s details) as well as other personal information.

**Collection of personal information**

We may collect information about you from different sources detailed below.

**Information you give us:**

When you access and browse our websites (including when you register for an event or fill in forms on our websites) and when you correspond with us by phone or email or other electronic means, you may give us information about yourself. The information you give us may include your name, payment processing information, postal address, email address, landline and/or mobile telephone number, delivery details, payment processing information, dietary and access requirements and information about your employment (including your job title, responsibilities and employer’s details) as well as other personal information.

**Information we collect about you:**

With regard to each of your visits to our website(s), we may also use cookies and other technologies to automatically collect the following information:

technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating systems and platform; and

information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstreams to, on and from our websites, products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks and mouse-overs), methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call us.

**Information we receive and collect from other sources:**

We may receive information about you from other websites operated by the Assemble Media Group or from the other services that we provide. We also work closely with third parties such as payment processors and app providers and may receive information about you from them. We may also collect information about you from publicly available sources, including publicly available content on social media.

**Cookies**

Our websites use cookies to distinguish you from other users. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse the websites and also allows us to improve our websites. 

**Our use of your personal information**

**We may use your personal information to:** | **How do we use personal information for this purpose?** | **What is the legal basis for us processing your information in this way?**  
---|---|---  
  
Provide you with goods and services

| 

We will need to use your personal information where this is necessary for us to perform our obligations under a contract with you, for example where you have purchased services from us, and to ensure your requirements are met at events.

| 

Using your personal information in this way is necessary for us to perform our contractual obligations to you.  
  
Ensure that your requirements are met at events

| 

We may use your personal information to better understand your requirements and preferences, so that we can provide you with a tailored experience.

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to look at your requirements so that we can personalise our events for you, to better meet your needs as a customer.  
  
Complete bookings you make through our website

| 

We will need to use your contact information (such as your email address or postal address) to assist you with any bookings you make through our website.

| 

Using your personal information in this way is necessary for us to perform our contractual obligations to you.  
  
Process your payments and protect against fraudulent transactions

| 

We may need to process your personal information in order to keep your payments safe and secure and protect against fraudulent transactions.

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to process personal information to keep our customers’ payments secure.  
  
Contact you for research purposes or to tell you about our special offers or other goods and services (provided you have consented to this)

| 

We will need to use your personal information (such as your email address and/or telephone number) to send you information about services that you may be interested in. Please note that we may also share your personal information with other entities in the Assemble Media Group for this purpose.

| 

We will ask for your consent before processing your information in this way.   
  
Diagnose problems with our server or administer our websites

| 

We may need to use personal information, such as your IP address, to diagnose server problems or administer our websites.

| 

We will ask for your consent to the use of cookies before processing.  
  
Analyse user traffic to measure use of our websites and to improve the content of our websites and our services

| 

We may sometimes use your personal information (e.g. your IP address) to measure use of our websites and assess the effectiveness of our site pages, including advertising on our sites. We may also use this personal information to improve the content of our websites and services.

| 

It is in our legitimate interest to look at user traffic so that we can improve our websites and better meet your needs as a customer.  
  
Comply with legal requirements and exercise or defend legal claims

| 

We may sometimes need to process personal information to comply with legal requirements to which we are subject (for example, in relation to health and safety).

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to process personal data for the purposes of complying with legal requirements to which we are subject.  
  
Assess how people move through our events where you have activated one of the apps available at an event

| 

We will need to use your personal information (such as information about your location) to understand how people have moved through an event that we host.

| 

It is in our legitimate interests to use your location information to monitor movement through our events.  
  
Where you consent to having your badge scanned at an event by us or a third party, contact you for research purposes or to tell you about special offers or other goods and services

| 

We may use your personal information (such as your email address and/or telephone number) to send you information about services that you may be interested in. Please note that we may also share your personal information with other entities in the Assemble Media Group and third parties for this purpose.

| 

By allowing your badge to be scanned at an event you are consenting to your information being processed in this way. If you do not wish for you information to be processed please do not scan your badge.  
  
**Transfers of personal information**

We may share your personal information with any brand within Assemble Media Group, in order to enable you to access the services, provide you with customer support and conduct the other activities described in this privacy policy. We use other companies, agents or contractors (“Service Providers”) to perform services on our behalf or to assist us with the provision of services to you. For example, we may engage Service Providers to provide market research, marketing (including competitions), advertising, communications, event management (including logistics, health and safety and audio-visual services), meetings and bookings (including accommodation), training, IT, hosting and other infrastructure, subscription and discount management, payment processing, and data cleansing and processing services. In the course of providing such services, these Service Providers may have access to your personal information. These third parties are contractually bound only to use personal information to perform the services that we hire them to provide. We will always use our best efforts to ensure that all the Service Providers we work with will keep your personal data secure.

We may also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * in the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets;
  * if any member of the Assemble Media Group or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data about its customers will be one of the transferred assets; and
  * if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation or in order to enforce our terms and conditions or other agreements, or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Assemble Media Group.

If you use one of our virtual products, e.g. Virtual Exhibitions, Directory Sites, Webinars etc., or choose to allow your badge to be scanned at an event, we may pass the information you provide to third parties. Generally this will be via a process whereby you, as the user, visit or interact with a third party e.g. visit a stand at an online exhibition, have your badge scanned or click on an asset branded and provided by a third party. In some instances, for example, a products listing site, you may reach out directly to a supplier or exhibitor who may contact you in return. In other instances our virtual products are sponsored and, in such cases the data you provided to us will be given to the sponsor. Generally, we will let you know at the time of collection if a product is sponsored. If you wish to change your contact preferences with an individual exhibitor/sponsor, please follow their own unsubscribe request details. Unsubscribing with Assemble Media Group or its associated brands will stop them from contacting you in the future, but not the individual third parties whom you have interacted with independently.

**Where we store your data**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the provision of services to you or the processing of your payment details. We will take all steps that are mandatory or reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and applicable data protection laws, including, where relevant, entering into EU standard contractual clauses (or equivalent measures) with the party outside the EEA receiving the data.

**Security of personal information**

We use administrative, technical, and physical measures to safeguard personal information against loss, theft and unauthorised uses, access or modifications.

Certain areas of our websites may be password protected. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share your password(s) with anyone.

Payments made via our websites are processed in a secure environment using software provided by third party providers.

**Third party websites and apps**

Our websites may contain links to and from third party websites and we may provide you with details of apps provided by third parties. Please note that if you follow a link to any of these websites or download an app, these websites and apps will have their own terms of use and privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility of liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites or apps.

**Your rights**

You have the following rights with respect to the personal information that we hold about you:

**Your right to access the information we hold about you**

You have the right to ask us whether or not we process your personal data and to request information on the purposes of data processing as well as confirmation on whether we use your personal information for these purposes only.

You can request access to the information we hold about you by contacting us using the contact details set out below. We will endeavour to make our file of your information available to you within 1 month, although occasionally we may not be able to give you access to the personal information we hold about you (for example, we may not be able to give you access if it would unreasonably affect someone else’s privacy or if giving you access poses a serious threat to someone’s life, health or safety).

You also have the right to be informed of the third parties to which we transfer your personal data within the scope of this privacy policy.

**Your right to have your information corrected or deleted**

If you have an account with us, you can sign into that account to update your personal information. If you have problems updating the information on your account or if you would like us to delete your information, or if you would like us to ask the third parties to whom we transfer your data within the scope of this privacy policy to update or delete your information, please send your request to tom.broughton@assemblemediagroup.com and we will action it as soon as possible.

**Your right to have your data transmitted to another organisation**

You have the right to ask us to stop processing your data, even where that processing is necessary for our legitimate interests (for example, where the processing is necessary for the legitimate commercial objectives we pursue in the course of our business), including the profiling we undertake to send you personalised offers, product recommendations and similar content. You also have the right to object to any results of a processing activity that prejudice your rights and that are conducted exclusively through automated systems.

You also have the right to ask us to stop processing your data for direct marketing purposes, including any profiling we undertake for the purposes of direct marketing. We will in any case only send you marketing communications if you have previously agreed to this, but if you change your mind you can easily unsubscribe from our marketing communications at any time by following the instructions included in these marketing communications.

Please note that, if you have consented to receive offers from our partners, our partners are responsible for taking account of your rights, including your right to opt-out of receiving offers from them. You may, however, at any time opt-out of receiving offers from third parties by logging in to your user account and changing the settings. If you had previously opted in, your personal data will cease to be transmitted to our partners from the time your request is processed.

**Your right to object to us processing your data**

Where we hold personal information about you with your consent or for the performance of a contract with you, you also have the right to ask us to provide you with the personal information we hold about you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and, where technically feasible, to transmit that data to another organisation.

**Making a complaint**

You have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authorities if you believe that we have not complied with applicable data protection laws. You also have a right to claim damages if processing of your personal information violates applicable data protection law.

**Changes to our privacy policy**

We reserve the right to amend this privacy policy at our sole discretion, without prior notice to you. We will notify you of any such changes (including when they will take effect). Your continued use of our services or our websites following the posting of changes to these terms means that you consent to those changes.

**Contacting us**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy, you can email us at [tom.broughton@assemblemediagroup.co.uk](mailto:tom.broughton@assemblemediagroup.co.uk) and if you wish to exercise your rights under applicable data protection law and this privacy policy, please contact us in writing at:

**The Data Protection Officer, Assemble Media Group, 81 Rivington Street, London EC2A 3AY**

**This version of the privacy policy is effective April 2018**
